Alright, the project starts then.
Okay? Obviously the first thing
you'll do is download the data.
You'll go to the location
that the business name has given you,
and you'll download the data on your laptop.
Next, you'll have to upload this Parquet file
to a data lake.
Now, what's a data lake? Data lake is something
where you can store any amount of data, any kind of data
for a very, very cheap price.
You wanna store Excel sheet, you wanna store parquet,
you wanna store log files, you wanna store media files,
you wanna store video files.
You can serve all of that in a data lake
at a very, very cheap price.
And on AWS data lake is built on
a service called as s threes.
I can search S3 here and click on S3.
I have many, many buckets here.
These are the buckets I'll tell you about them shortly.
These are many buckets that you have here.
A combination of this, all of this becomes your data lake.
Now what are these different things you see here?
These are called as buckets, okay? General purpose buckets.
These are, and you will create something called as mission,
D-H-H-O-F-N-Y-C-T-L-C, bucket in your account.
So when I click on this, I have a folder
here called A raw, okay?
I can create folders here
and I can organize the data by folders.
And within this, as called as hv, FHV, why HV FHV?
Because I am downloading the high volume FHV data.
And here I have uploaded the Parque file,
which you'll do shortly.
So the first step for you would be to get a bucket created.
Okay? Now, who's gonna get the bucket?
You will not do that in every company.
We have cloud engineers, you may call them cloud engineers,
we call them cloud infrastructure engineers.
There's a cloud engineering team, which is responsible
for creating these buckets.
So you'll email them, Hey,
I want a bucket for my new project.
They will create it for you in the hands-on video
that you'll now watch in a few minutes.
I've given you a script.
Now you'll run the script
and it'll automatically create the bucket for you.
You imagine that that script is being run
by the cloud engineering team to create the bucket for you,
but here you are running it yourself.
So once you have the bucket ready,
you wanna create the folders and upload the file here.
All of this is shown to you in the next few videos.
So that is the first step, right?
You, you have downloaded the data.
Now you have uploaded that into the data lake.
Now this is still a park data.
It is, this is this folder,
and this bucket is like a container, right?
It is like your hard desk.
You are able to store whatever you wanna store,
except on Windows or Mac.
You can open a a video file and view it.
But here, you can't open the que file for that matter.
Even you, even on your laptop, you can't open a que file.
So how can you give access to the analyst to this data?
So that's the next step, right? Talk to you soon.